Guide to the New York Brewery, Spokane, Washington, Papers 1887-1904
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
New York Brewery, Spokane, Washington, Papers
1887-1904
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Cage 7
New York Brewery (Spokane, Wash.)
6 Linear feet of shelf space 8 Boxes + Oversize
Letterbooks, ledgers, accounts, reports and other papers of the New York Brewery, Spokane, Washington.
The New York Brewery was founded in 1886 by Rudolph Gorkow. In 1900 it was purchased and its management was consolidated with that of Henco Brewery as the Spokane Brewing and Malting Company, although it continued to function under its own name as a branch operator. In 1903 the branch closed.
In 1902, the Galland-Burke Brewing and Malting Company was also purchased by the Spokane Brewing and Malting Company. All three breweries were operated, at least initially, as branch breweries. The company remained in business until the mid-thirties when the assets were sold to the Sicks-Rainier brewing interests of Puget Sound.
Letterbooks, ledgers, accounts, reports and other papers of the New York Brewery, Spokane, Washington.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Julius Galland, Jr. donated this collection, as part of the Spokane Brewing and Malting Company papers, to the Washington State University Libraries in 1937.
These papers were seperated from The Spokane Brewing and Malting Company, Spokane, Washington, Papers, 1891-1932 (Cage 14).
The papers of the two other predecessor companies were also separated from those records:
Henco Brewery, Spokane, Washington, Papers, 1899-1909 (Cage 1)
Galland-Burke Brewing and Malting Company, Spokane, Washington, Papers, 1891-1913 (Cage 13)
Smith, George Vinal. History of Spokane Brewing and Malting Company, Spokane, Washington, 1887-1916. Washington State University, 1967. (Unpublished thesis.)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
New York Brewery (Spokane, Wash.) -- Records and correspondence.; Spokane Brewing and Malting Company -- Records and correspondence.; Spokane Brewing and Malting Company.
Brewing industry -- Washington (State) -- Spokane.
Washington (State); Businesses and Corporations
- Letterbooks, 1892-1903; 17 volumes. (Box 1-6)
- Materials Books, 1887-1904; 7 volumes. (Box 7)
- Cash Books, 1891-1894; 4 volumes. (Box 7)
- Cash Books, 1894-1897; 4 volumes. (Box 8)
- Cash Books, 1901-1902; 1 volume. (Box 8)
- Cash Books, 1897-1902; 6 volumes. (Box Oversize)
- Ledger, 1892-1900; 4 volumes. (Box Oversize)
- Day Book, 1891-1902; 5 volumes. (Box Oversize)
- Record of Fermented Liquors, 1887-1904; 11 volumes. (Box Oversize)
- Trial Balance Books, 1896-1902; 4 volumes. (Box Oversize)